HEYSEM CIL FRONTEND DEVELOPER

E-mail: heysemcil@gmail.com
Phone: +1 6479398693
Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/heysemcil
Address: Ottawa, ON

GitHub: www.github.com/heysemcil.com

Portfolio: www.heysemcil.com

SUMMARY

A frontend developer enthusiast with 3+ years of work experience and 2 years of experience in frontend development. Especially involved in web development using TypeScript, React, Redux. Excited to learn new technologies, innovation and problem solving.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, ES6, Python

Frontend: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Jquery, React.js, Redux.js, AJAX, Axios, Yup, Formik, Cypress.js

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, JSON Web Token (JWT), Firebase, RESTful APIs, Docker,

Styling: CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components

Database: SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose, ORM, ODM

Tools: Postman, VSCode, Git, GitHub, Netlify, Vercel

Soft Skills: Thorough and pay attention to detail, Able to write computer programs, Persistent and determined, Flexible and open

to change, Able to use my own initiative and have problem-solving skills, Self-learner

PROJECTS

- StockApp is an online single-page web application that enables you to manage orders and inventory with the ability to get, add, edit, or delete products, firms, brands, sales, and purchases. Technical stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Material.UI in the front-end, React context and Redux Toolkit for state management.
- **Fireblog App** is a personal blog app aiming to create blog posts using firebase realtime-database and display them on the dashboard. Adding, deleting and updating blog posts can be done. In the project, firebase realtime-database library was used for storing data, Material UI library for styling, react-router library for page transitions, formik and yup libraries for form structure and validation, and react-toastify library for notifications. In addition, firebase was used for login and authorization processes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Brc Nail Studio, US (Remote)

May 2024 - Aug 2024

- Developed corporate website and application, adhering to deadlines %100.
- Utilized TypeScript to develop a large-scale React-based project, resulting in a 40% reduction in development time and improved code quality.
- Ensured Client satisfaction by 100%, leading customer satisfaction and sales numbers by 10%.
- Integrated 3rd party reservation services providing app-service compliance 100%.
- Deployed website implementing CI/CD processes utilizing the Vercel app.

Field Representative, CPE Painting & Decoration Inc, Toronto

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

• Conducted field sales activities for a leading company in the paint industry.

Web Development Certificate, Clarusway (480+ hours, 6 months)

- Identified potential customers in target markets, expanding the customer portfolio.
- Increased sales and ensured customer satisfaction by highlighting product features and advantages

International Sales Manager, Otomatsan Makine San. Ltd, Istanbul

Aug 2018 - Nov 2021

May 2024

- Managed a distributorship unit to oversee the sales of vending machines worldwide. Installed thousands of vending machines worldwide with +35 exclusive country distributors and hundreds of sub-dealers.
- Identified and trained new candidates who are interested in becoming our distributors. Formulated the business plan with the candidate who wants to be the country distributor and presented it to management.
- Motivated and guided the team by consistently monitoring and aligning daily, weekly, and monthly goals, ensuring sustained energy and focus toward achieving objectives.

EDUCATION

 ILAC College, Sales and Marketing, Toronto, Ontario, Canada Uludag University, Business Administration, Bachelor's Degree Turkey 	2021 – 2023 2015 – 2019
CERTIFICATIONS	
• Front-End Web Development Certificate, Arabuleu & Udemig (360+ hours, 6 months)	Mar 2023